What is your role as a designer?
As Elena mentioned, I have many roles.
I am a designer,
and we have our own brand of designers,
and we also do some design services for companies.
At the same time, I teach digital fashion in the school.
Today, we are more of a designer
to share with you
our experiences and experiences
of using Clou software
in different parts of our work.
The topic I am going to share today is
Clou design from design to completion.
As a fashion designer,
we often encounter a lot of problems
in our daily design and product development.
For example,
how to use Clou software
in our design process,
how to reduce our development costs,
and how to make our creativity a reality.
In such a process,
we also encounter a lot of difficulties.
For example,
we are constantly adjusting and modifying
a certain style.
In fact,
it will take a lot of time and energy,
and it will also be a lot of waste.
In the process of communicating with fashion,
sometimes our description
is not so direct and specific,
or everyone understands each other better.
When we understand each other better,
there will be some differences.
So in fact,
the development process
is actually a relatively painful and long process.
With Clou software,
we can solve these problems
relatively quickly
in different dimensions.
Today, we are going to talk about
a few aspects of the content.
One is our current development pain points,
and the other is
some awareness of Clou software.
The third is
our
core features of Clou software,
and the last is
some of the cases we have done.
Let me share them with you.
I think
as an independent designer,
the current state of work
is that
as an independent designer
or as a designer
based on creativity,
in fact,
what we lack most
is our rich ideas.
However,
the difficulty is
how to quickly and efficiently
put these ideas into practice.
In fact,
there are some fundamental differences
between an independent designer
and a commercial brand.
A commercial brand is actually
more data-driven,
more sincere,
and more satisfied with
the aesthetic needs of
the general consumer.
It may be simpler
and more concise.
As an independent designer,
in fact,
many times,
we design based on
our aesthetic needs.
Sometimes,
we want to try
something that
some commercial brands
are not willing to do.
To put it simply,
we want to design
something more complex
and more difficult
to achieve.
In this process,
in fact,
we will encounter
a lot of problems.
Before we use
a commercial brand,
we usually
make about
600 or 700
samples
per sample.
In the process,
for example,
if we make
the same sample
and adjust the details,
we adjust
one or two
or even three
small details,
we may need
to do it again.
Otherwise,
we may need
to do it again.
Or,
if we make
the same sample
and adjust the fabric
of different textures,
the result is completely different.
We may need
to do it again.
There are a lot of
such things.
In fact,
in the commercial business,
from the end,
it is all about
cost.
Especially,
we basically
have to do
two series
and two press conferences
for our own brand
for a year.
In addition,
we do design services
for other customers.
In fact,
we still have a lot
to do.
For example,
this year,
in March,
we did a show
in Zhuanghui,
Zhuangzhou.
Basically,
we need
45 to 50 looks
for a show.
Basically,
we need three products
for each look.
Basically,
we need 150 products.
In fact,
those who do
make-up
know that
if we adjust
the big board
from the previous
to the white one,
the first,
the second,
the third,
and finally
make it into one,
we need a lot of time
and a lot of cost
to do this process.
In addition,
I think
if we do it
in a traditional way,
in fact,
the whole cycle
is also very long.
Because
our current
studio
is in Shanghai.
In fact,
many of our co-workers
are not
all in-house.
Not all the
furniture
and clothes
are in our studio.
We are
working with
different factories
to coordinate
and do
sample development.
In fact,
every detail adjustment,
every
surface material adjustment,
and every
design adjustment
is actually
a more complicated
communication process.
Because
everyone knows
that in fact,
the masters
and sample workers
in the factory
also have
their own ideas.
In addition,
if it is not
face-to-face
specific communication,
sometimes
it is difficult
to do
something
particularly specific.
And the cycle
of this communication
will also be very long.
Usually,
our traditional development
may take
four to six weeks
from painting
to
picking
back
the
fabric
and then
making
it.
It may take
more than
8 to 12 weeks
for the entire
series of
development.
Sometimes
it may
be
more.
In addition,
we have
some cross-department
coordination.
For example,
we have some
technical data,
including
the purchase
of some
sample
material,
and so on.
It is necessary
to communicate
with different
departments,
different
regions,
and people
who may
not be
in the same
city.
In fact,
these contents
have greatly
increased
the cost
and efficiency
of our
software.
In conclusion,
we think
that
there are several
advantages
of
cross-department
software.
One is that
it is light,
high,
and small.
In fact,
in the past,
we may need
to design
in the office
and draw
with paper
and pencil.
Now,
when we go on a
business trip
and have
ideas,
we may
have to
make some
adjustments
to the
model
and make
some
changes
to the
model.
In fact,
it is very
convenient
at any time
and in
cross-department software,
the process
of matching
the
2D
and 3D
models
is very
precise.
In fact,
we started
to use
cross-department software
a lot
in the past.
It is not only
a tool for
version testing,
but it can also
be used
to design
tools that
help designers
achieve a lot of
visual effects.
In cross-department software,
there are
continuous
and different
styles of
board
and fabric
matching.
In fact,
these assets
accumulated
every season
can be
transferred
and adjusted
on the basis
of
cross-department software
to improve
the efficiency
of our development.
There is also
a cross-department
configuration.
We are not only
doing some
design services
for the
body,
but we also
do a lot of
virtual video
service projects.
Sometimes
we may
put
the video content
into other 3D
software
for rendering.
The characters
and costumes
are still
built
and made
in
Clo.
In addition,
we can
make a 3D video
with the
digital assets
such as
drawing,
clothing,
and so on.
So,
I think
these advantages
can be
better
and more efficient
to help
designers
in the development
of design
and to realize
the rich
ideas
in our minds.
Now,
let's talk about
some key applications.
In fact,
I mentioned
the 3D version
and the 3D
version
before.
This is actually
a very good
and efficient tool.
I think
there are two types
of designers
at the moment.
One type
is a designer
who can
complete the 3D
version
very well.
A designer
like this
is actually
more friendly
to the Clo 3D
software.
You can
make the 3D version
at the 2D window
at any time
and use
3D modeling
to make
the 3D version.
However,
in fact,
some tools
for adjusting
the 3D version
in the Clo software
can also
help us
to make
a 3D version
that can see
the visual effects.
And
even if we
don't know
how to make
the 3D version at all,
in fact,
in the 2D window,
we can still
import
an existing
3D version
into it.
Then,
we can
make
a 3D version
of the 3D version
in the Clo software
to see
the visual effects
of the 3D version
in the Clo software.
Then,
we can use
this 3D version
to communicate
with the designer.
In fact,
it will also
greatly improve
the efficiency
of our communication.
And
there is
a particularly good
content
in the Clo software,
which is
its fabric library.
In fact,
there are many
richer fabrics
in the fabric library,
including
the design of
the design
library.
In fact,
the design library
is also
a place
where designers
can imagine
the product
before they
develop the
actual product.
Moreover,
the fabric
included in
the fabric library
not only
has
the fixed
color,
we can also
adjust the color
and pattern
of these fabrics
through the function
of fabric editing.
I won't
talk about
fabric editing
in this video.
This is
actually
one of our cases.
Previously,
we made a digital
virtual fashion show.
There is a clothing design
on it.
In fact,
it is very complicated.
It is a men's shirt,
but I made a lot
of division
on this shirt.
We can have a big picture.
In the past,
and it also
has the effect
of smoothing.
In the past,
such styles,
such as
the position
and proportion
of the division line,
etc.,
if we do
this,
it will be
very convenient
and efficient.
This is actually
what we are giving
our design service customers
when providing
some styles
for development.
The same style
we can
match
different colors
of fabrics
in the software
to make
different color
effects.
This also
greatly
reduces
the cost
of our development.
It can be more intuitive
and make
customers
have more
choice
to choose from.
Yes,
the following are
our cases.
The first case
is what I did
before.
I did a show
for Qipilang.
Then,
this is actually
a competition selection.
In the pre-season
of the competition selection,
we used
the design
and draft
of this style
in the form
of 3D modeling.
Our theme
is
parallel time and space.
In fact,
we want
to do
two kinds of effects.
One is
the real face
and the other is
the modeling effect.
One is
we imagine
in a real-time space
there is a concept
of parallel to
the real-time space
now.
And then,
the other kind of
modeling effect
we used
this kind of
lightning effect
to make
a kind of
sculpture.
In fact,
it can not only
satisfy us
from technology
to achieve
a dress.
In fact,
for designers,
it has a lot of
artistic effects
that can better
help us
to understand
the content of
the proposal.
Let me show you.
We have
three themes
in this series.
The first theme
is called
parallel universe
to the real-time space.
This series is
a little bit
deeper
than that.
The second one
is called
parallel universe
called
moon planet.
The moon planet
is more
leisurely
and
more
relaxing.
The third one
is called
parallel universe
to the real-time space.
The planet
to the real-time space
is made
with the theme
of the brand
and the style
of the brand.
Yes.
This is
the effect
of
modeling
the model
from
the cloud 3D software
to the model
in the end.
However,
we also changed
the background
of the platform
to a background
of modeling
in the 3D software.
Yes.
This is the
second project.
The second project
is that
we made
a virtual
virtual video show
for a brand
called
Hongdu
in Beijing.
The production
of this video
is mostly
done
by AI tools.
But
we also
made
all the clothing
produced
in this video
into food.
These
are
screenshots
of our
video.
Yes.
This is
the effect
of the
clothes
we made
later.
Before making
these clothes,
we also
made
modeling
in 3D software.
Yes.
The most important
thing is
that I think
this cloud software
is a good point
for our application.
In the process
of making
this video,
there are
many
differences
and many
concepts
of composition.
In fact,
we can
directly
meet
our requirements.
So,
our method
is to
build the clothes
in 3D software first.
Then,
what kind of
perspective
do we need?
What kind of composition
We first
render
this picture
and then
produce AI
based on
this rendered
picture.
The video
generated
can basically
reach
our
lens
with a lot of extension.
The third case
is actually
the case in our pet store.
We not only
have our own
pet brand,
but also
have our own pet brand.
The pet brand
is the effect picture
of some pet stores
that we created
with AI.
In fact,
we also made
this tablet
in 3D software
and finally made a pet.
I think
the better point is that
we are not particularly familiar
with the structure
of the pet store.
But
there are some
pet models
in our software.
In fact,
we have to
make some
adjustments
to the structure
of the pet
in this process
to understand
the structure
of the pet
and how to adjust
its volume.
In fact,
for some
completely unknown
spaces,
we can make mistakes
at a low cost
in the software.
The last one
is
a virtual video
made
for a fabric company.
This virtual video
is
almost
all used
in the software of
Clo3D.
We use AI
to make
this material
with the texture
of the fabric.
All of these
static
and dynamic
clothes
are all made
with 3D software.
And
the better point is that
it can have
the effect of
real people wearing it
and at the same time
it can also
extend
people.
There is only
a mid-air effect
of 3D clothing.
In fact,
these have greatly
improved
the possibility
of our designers
to be creative.
I think
for us,
there are a few
core values
of Clo3D software.
First,
I think it can be
precise and precise.
When we
designed the concept
for a season,
we did not
really
develop the paper
in advance.
We can
run the entire
design process
in the software
once.
In fact,
this can be
more accurate
and make
the landing
in the later period
can greatly improve
the accuracy
of our landing.
Second,
in fact,
the efficiency
is a problem.
This efficiency
is also reflected
in our time cost,
that is,
we can be faster.
And
there is also
our location,
that is,
we can do this
thing at any time.
In the past,
for example,
you can only do
this kind of thing
in the office
with a board,
a chair,
and a board.
Now,
we often have meetings,
we can solve
such problems
one by one.
In fact,
the last is
the cost control.
In fact,
we also talked about
the development
of our virtual sample.
In the end,
our current situation
is that
many times
we only do
100 samples,
that is,
we no longer
need to do
white paper.
We realize
all the previous
parts in the software.
In the end,
when it comes to
real fabric,
we can only do
100.
This can actually
solve this problem.
In the past,
many times
when we were
doing design development,
we needed
experience to drive,
but now
many times
we can use
design,
use data to drive
to solve such problems.
Okay,
this is basically
what we want
to share
with you today.
I hope that
we will have
more opportunities
to communicate
how to use
Colossus software
better.
We can
make our creativity
more efficient
in different dimensions
and
more rich.
We also hope
that we have
more opportunities
to use
Colossus software
to do more
communication with you.
Thank you.